Guide to the Archives Foreign File (AFF), Section 2
Archives Foreign File (AFF), Section 2
- Box: 40, Folder: 9, Publication (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Item 11: For the Just Cause of the Workers and People of Algeria - Decisions of the International Trade Union Committee for Solidarity with the Workers and People of Algeria, 1958; Publication (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Item 12: A Youth Conference worthy of the International Working Class Movement: Reports presented to the First World Trade Union Conference of Young Workers, Closing speech to the Conference by Louis Saillant, Resolutions and decisions, 1958; Publication (Box 40, Folder 9)
    Author: World Trade Union Conference of Young Workers
  - Item 13: Ten Years' Activity of the World Federation of Trade Unions in the United Nations, 1956; Publication (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Item 14: The Peoples Demand National Independence - Solidarity of the WFTU with the Peoples Fighting Against Colonial Oppression and for National Independence, 1957; Publication (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Item 15: Wages Automation and Hours of Work - Three Fields of Present-Day Trade Union Activity, 1957; Publication (Box 40, Folder 9)
- Box: 40, Folder: 10, Publication (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Twenty Years Under the Fascist Dictatorship of General Franco: The Lives and Struggles of the Spanish Workers, 1960; Publication (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Item 2: A Valuable Contribution to the Fight Against the Monopolies, 1964; Publication (Box 40, Folder 10)
    Author: World Trade Union Committee for Consultation and United Action Against the Monopolies
  - Item 3: The 116-Day Strike of the American Steelworkers: An Analysis by the Secretariat of the Trade Unions International of Metal and Engineering Industries (Trade Department of the WFTU), 1959; Publication (Box 40, Folder 10)
    Author: G. Adduci and J. Marillier
  - Item 4: Working Women Shape Their Future: 2nd International Trade Union Conference on the Problems of Working Women, 1964; Publication (Box 40, Folder 10)
    Author: International Trade Union Conference on the Problems of Working Women
  - Item 5: The WFTU in the Service of the Workers of All Countries, 1960; Publication (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Item 6: Texts and Documents adopted by the Fifth World Trade Union Congress, 1961; Publication (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Item 7: Let the Alliance of Workers and Trade Unions Oppose the Alliance of Monopolies, 1962; Publication (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Item 8: Korea for the Koreans: The Struggle Against US Imperialism in South Korea and for the Unification of the Country, 1963; Publication (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Item 9: For a German Peace Treaty for a Peaceful Settlement of the West Berlin Problem Against War Provocations, 1961; Publication (Box 40, Folder 10)
    Author: International Trade Union Conference for a German Peace Treaty, a Peaceful Settlement of the West Berlin Problem, and Against War Provocations
  - Item 10: A Valuable Contribution to the Fight Against Monopolies, 1964; Publication (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Item 11: The 116-Day Strike of the American Steelworkers: An Analysis by the Secretariat of the Trade Unions International of Metal and Engineering Industries (Trade Department of the WFTU), 1959; Publication (Box 40, Folder 10)
    Author: G. Adducci and J. Marillier
- Box: 40, Folder: 11, Publication (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Programme of Trade Union Action at the Present Stage of the Defence of the Workers' Interests and Rights, 1961; Publication (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Item 2: Programme of Trade Union Action at the Present Stage of the Defence of the Workers' Interests and Rights, 1961; Publication (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Item 3: Programme of Trade Union Action at the Present Stage of the Defence of the Workers' Interests and Rights, 1961; Publication (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Item 4: Programme of Trade Union Action at the Present Stage of the Defence of the Workers' Interests and Rights, 1961; Publication (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Item 5: For a German Peace Treaty for a Peaceful Settlement of the West Berlin Problem Against War Provocations, 1961; Publication (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Item 6: For the Abolition of Colonialism, 1961; Publication (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Item 7: International trade union conference for a German peace treaty a peaceful settlement of the West Berlin problem and against war provocations, 1961; Publication (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Item 8: International trade union conference for a German peace treaty a peaceful settlement of the West Berlin problem and against war provocations, 1961; Publication (Box 40, Folder 11)
    Notes: 2 copies
  - Item 9: Social Security Charter adopted by the Fifth World Trade Union Congress, 1961; Publication (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Item 10: The WFTU and the Tasks of the Trade Union Movement, 1961; Publication (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Item 11: The WFTU and the Tasks of the Trade Union Movement, 1961; Publication (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Item 12: The WFTU and the Tasks of the Trade Union Movement, 1961; Publication (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Item 13: The WFTU and the Tasks of the Trade Union Movement, 1961; Publication (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Item 14: The WFTU in the Service of the Workers of All Countries, 1960; Publication (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Item 15: For the Abolition of Colonialism, 1961; Publication (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Item 16: South Vietnam - The Just Struggle of the Workers and the People for: National Independence, Peace, Prosperity, 1962; Publication (Box 40, Folder 11)
    Author: Worker's Association for the Liberation of South Vietnam
- Box: 40, Folder: 12, Publication (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Communist Labor Tactics in the Colonial and Former Colonial Countries, 1961; Publication (Box 40, Folder 12)
    Author: George Lichtblau
  - Item 2: Draft Programme of Trade Union Action at the present stage of the defence of the workers' interests and rights, 1961; Publication (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Item 3: For International United Action to End Apartheid: The Curse of South Africa, 1961; Publication (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Item 4: The WFTU and the Tasks of the Trade Union Movement, 1961; Publication (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Item 5: Latin America: Armed Terror Against Trade Unions, 1960; Publication (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Item 6: Latin America: Armed Terror Against Trade Unions, 1960; Publication (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Item 7: Leipzig 1963: For Talks to Advance International Trade Union Unity - Plenary Conference of the World Trade Union Committee for Consultation and Unity of Action against the Monopolies, Publication (Box 40, Folder 12)
    Author: World Trade Union Committee for Consultation and Unity of Action Against the Monopolies
  - Item 8: Leipzig 1963: For Talks to Advance International Trade Union Unity - Plenary Conference of the World Trade Union Committee for Consultation and Unity of Action against the Monopolies, Publication (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Item 9: An International Meeting of Women Workers, 1964; Publication (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Item 10: Democratic Trade Union Rights: A Powerful Weapon of the Working Class - Documents of the second meeting of the International Trade Union and Legal Commission for the Defence and Extension of Trade Union Rights and the Protection of the Victims of Anti-Tra, 1963; Publication (Box 40, Folder 12)
    Author: International Trade Union and Legal Commission for the Defence and Extension of Trade Union Rights and the Protection of the Victims of Anti-Trade Union Repression
  - Item 11: A Fighting Record: The World Federation of Trade Unions against Apartheid, Publication (Box 40, Folder 12)
- Box: 40, Folder: 13, Publication (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Texts and Documents adopted by the Fifth World Trade Union Congress, 1961; Publication (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Item 2: Democratic Trade Union Rights: A Powerful Weapon of the Working Class - Documents of the second meeting of the International Trade Union and Legal Commission for the Defence and Extension of Trade Union Rights and the Protection of the Victims of Anti-Tra, 1963; Publication (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Item 3: Democratic Trade Union Rights: A Powerful Weapon of the Working Class - Documents of the second meeting of the International Trade Union and Legal Commission for the Deference and Extension of Trade Union Rights and the Protection of the Victims of Anti-T, 1963; Publication (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Item 4: WFTU Appeal to the workers and trade unions of the world for thr 50th anniversary of the Great October Socialist Revolution, Publication (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Item 5: The WFTU and the Tasks of the Trade Union Movement, 1961; Publication (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Item 6: From Oil Lamp to Electric Power Station: Mongolia's Giant Leap from the Middle Ages to Socialism, Publication (Box 40, Folder 13)
    Author: Lise London
- Box: 40, Folder: 14, Publication (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Report: Joint Trade Union Action for the Development of International Trade and Economic relations in the Interests of the Workers and Peoples, 1966; Publication (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Item 2: Constitution of the World Federation of Trade Unions adopted by the World Trade Conference October 3, 1945, 1967; Publication (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Item 3: Nevermore!, 1965; Publication (Box 40, Folder 14)
    Author: Trade Unions International of Workers in Commerce
  - Item 4: Vocational Training: more than a concern - a necessity, 1968; Publication (Box 40, Folder 14)
    Author: World Trade Union Conference on Vocational Training
  - Item 5: Welfare Freedom Peace - Proceedings of the 34th session of the Executive Committee of the WFTU, 1967; Publication (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Item 6: Workers and Trade Union against Apartheid, 1967; Publication (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Item 7: The Paths to Trade Union Unity, 1965; Publication (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Item 8: In the Thick of the Struggle, 1965; Publication (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Item 9: Common Action in the Common Interest: WFTU-AATUF Consultative Conference of Solidarity of African and European Trade Unions, 1969; Publication (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Item 10: Decisions and Resolutions, 1965; Publication (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Item 11: Break Down the Barriers - Documents of the World Trade Union Conference for the development of International Trade and Economic Relations in the Interests of the Workers and Peoples, 1966; Publication (Box 40, Folder 14)
    Author: World Trade Union Conference for the Development of International Trade and Economic Relations in the Interests of the Workers and Peoples
  - Item 12: WFTU Appeal to the workers and trade unions of the world for the 50th anniversary of the Great October Socialist Revolution, Publication (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Item 13: In the Thick of the Struggle, 1965; Publication (Box 40, Folder 14)
- Box: 40, Folder: 15, Publication (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: Charter on Vocational Training adopted by the World Trade Union Conference on Vocational Training, 1968; Publication (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Item 2: Against Colonialism and Agression in Vietnam, 1965; Publication (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Item 3: Break Down the Barriers - Documents of the World Trade Union Conference for the Development of International Trade and Economic Relations in the Interests of the Workers and Peoples, 1966; Publication (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Item 4: Break Down the Barriers - Documents of the World Trade Union Conference for the development of International Trade and Economic Relations in the Interests of the Workers and Peoples, 1966; Publication (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Item 5: From Oil Lamp to Electric Power Station: Mongolia's Giant Leap from the Middle Ages to Socialism, Publication (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Item 6: In the Thick of the Struggle, 1965; Publication (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Item 7: In the Thick of the Struggle, 1965; Publication (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Item 8: International Conference of Shipbuilding and Ship-Repair Workers, 1965; Publication (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Item 9: The October Socialist Revolution and the International Trade Union Movement, 1967; Publication (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Item 10: The Paths to Trade Union Unity, 1965; Publication (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Item 11: The WFTU Outlines for the Future: The 16th session of the General Council, 1966; Publication (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Item 12: Woman as Worker, and Trade Unionist, Publication (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Item 13: Workers and Trade Unions Against Apartheid, 1967; Publication (Box 40, Folder 15)
- Box: 41, Folder: 1, Publication (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Against Colonialism and Aggression in Vietnam, 1965; Publication (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Item 2: The Just Cause of the Korean People Will Triumph, Publication (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Item 3: Towards the 7th Trade Union Congress: Reports and documents from the 18th session of General Council, 1968; Publication (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Item 4: Woman as Worker, and Trade Unionist, 1967; Publication (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: The Paths to Trade Union Unity, 1965; Publication (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: Common Action in the Common Interest: WFTU-AATUF Special Bulletin Number 1 - 1969, Publication (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Item 7: Common Action in the Common Interest: WFTU-AATUF Special Bulletin Number 2 -1969, Publication (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Item 8: Common Action in the Common Interest: WFTU-AATUF Special Bulletin Number 3 - 1969, Publication (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Item 9: Common Action in the Common Interest: WFTU-AATUF Special Bulletin Number 3 - 1969, Publication (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Item 10: Common Action in the Common Interest: WFTU-AATUF Special Bulletin Number 4 - 1969, Publication (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Item 11: Common Action in the Common Interest: WFTU-AATUF Special Bulletin Number 5 - 1969, Publication (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Item 12: Common Action in the Common Interest: WFTU-AATUF Special Bulletin Number 5 - 1969, Publication (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Item 13: Common Action in the Common Interest: WFTU-AATUF Special Bulletin Number 6 - 1969, Publication (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Item 14: Common Action in the Conmon Interest: WFTU-AATUF Special Bulletin Number 6 - 1969, Publication (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Item 15: Giuseppe Di Vittorio and the World Federation of Trade Unions, 1967; Publication (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Item 16: Illiteracy - Blight of the Twentieth Century: World Trade Union Conference on Functional Literacy, 1969; Publication (Box 41, Folder 1)
- Box: 41, Folder: 2, Publication (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Charter on Vocational Training adopted by the World Trade Union Conference on Vocational Training, 1968; Publication (Box 41, Folder 2)
    Author: Sve?tova odborova federace. Mezin. konf.
  - Item 2: Charter on Vocational Training adopted by the World Trade Union Conference on Vocational Training, 1968; Publication (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Item 3: Report on the second point of the agenda: Development of the WFTU's work in the United Nations and its specialised agencies, Publication (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Item 4: Vserminaia Federatsiia Profsolvzov, 1965; Publication (Box 41, Folder 2)
    Author: Pimenov, Petr Timofeevich
  - Item 5: Giuseppe Di Vittorio and the World Federation of Trade Unions, 1966; Publication (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Item 6: Decisions and Resolutions, 1965; Publication (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Item 7: Appeal to the workers and trade unions of the world, 1969; Publication (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Item 8: Common Action in the Common Interest: WFTU-AATUF Consultative Conference of Solidarity of African and European Trade Unions, 1969; Publication (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Item 9: Common Action in the Common Interest: WFTU-AATUF Consultative Conference of Solidarity of African and European Trade Unions, 1969; Publication (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Item 10: The Commemorative International Trade Union Assembly on the occasion of the 50th anniversary of the Great October Socialist Revolution 1917: Leningrad, 30-31 October 1967, Publication (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Item 11: The Needs of the Hour in Our Struggle, 1966; Publication (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Item 12: The WFTU Outlines for the Future: The 16th session of the General Council, 1966; Publication (Box 41, Folder 2)
- Box: 41, Folder: 3, Publication (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: The World Federation of Trade Unions: Study of a Failure in Internationalism, Publication (Box 41, Folder 3)
    Author: John Windmuller
- Box: 41, Folder: 4, Publication (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: The World Federation of Trade Unions and Vietnam: 4 - December 1968, Publication (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Item 2: The WFTU and the ICATU, 1968; Publication (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Item 3: The World Federation of Trade Unions and Vietnam: 1 - March 1968, Publication (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Item 4: The World Federation of Trade Unions and Vietnam: 1 - March 1969, Publication (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Item 5: The World Federation of Trade Unions and Vietnam: 1 - September 1967, Publication (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Item 6: The World Federation of Trade Unions and Vietnam: 2 - December 1967, Publication (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Item 7: The World Federation of Trade Unions and Vietnam: 2 - June 1968, Publication (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Item 8: The World Federation of Trade Unions and Vietnam: 2 - September 1969, Publication (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Item 9: The World Federation of Trade Unions and Vietnam: 3 - October 1968, Publication (Box 41, Folder 4)
- Box: 41, Folder: 5, Publication (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: The World Federation of Trade Unions and Indochina: December 1972 - The WFTU and Vietnam No. 18, Publication (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Item 2: The World Federation of Trade Unions and Indochina: June 1974 - The WFTU and Vietnam No. 21, Publication (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Item 3: The World Federation of Trade Unions and Indochina: April 1971 - The WFTU and Vietnam No. 13, Publication (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Item 4: The World Federation of Trade Unions and Indochina: August 1970, The WFTU and Vietnam No. 11, Publication (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Item 5: The World Federation of Trade Unions and Indochina: August 1971 - The WFTU and Vietnam No. 14, Publication (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Item 6: The World Federation of Trade Unions and Indochina: August 1972 - The WFTU and Vietnam No. 17, Publication (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Item 7: The World Federation of Trade Unions and Indochina: December 1970 - The WFTU and Vietnam No. 12, Publication (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Item 8: The World Federation of Trade Unions and Indochina: December 1971 - The WFTU and Vietnam No. 15, Publication (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Item 9: The World Federation of Trade Unions and Indochina: May 1973 - The WFTU and Vietnam No. 19, Publication (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Item 10: The World Federation of Trade Unions and Vietnam: 1 - April 1970, Publication (Box 41, Folder 5)
- Box: 41, Folder: 6, Publication (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: International Conference of the Trade Section of Commercial and Clerical Employees in Commerce and Industry, 1950; Publication (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Item 2: Press Information, No. 66 - 7, 1966; Publication (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Item 3: Resolutions Adopted by the ILO Advisory Committee on Salaried Employees and Professional Workers at its 6th Session, 1967; Publication (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Item 4: Short Report of the International Congress of Commercial, Clerical, & Technical Employees, 1920; Publication (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Item 5: Correspondence: Aux membres du Bureau et du Conseil General de la FSM, 1971; Publication (Box 41, Folder 6)
    Author: Pierre Gensous
  - Item 6: Common Action in the Common Interest: WFTU-AATUF Consultative Conference of Solidarity of African and European Trade Unions, 1969; Publication (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Item 7: Containerisation and its Social Consequences for Dockers, 1969; Publication (Box 41, Folder 6)
    Author: International Dockers' Seminar on Problems of Rationalisation and Containerisation in Ports and Docks and Its Social Consequences for the Workers
  - Item 8: Giuseppe Di Vittorio and the World Federation of Trade Unions, 1967; Publication (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Item 9: Illiteracy - Blight of the Twentieh Century: World Trade Union Conference on Functional Literacy, 1969; Publication (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Item 10: The Commemorative International Trade Union Assembly on the occasion of the 50th anniversary of the Great October Socialist Revolution 1917: Leningrad, 30-31 October 1967, Publication (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Item 11: The Commemorative International Trade Union Assembly on the occasion of the 50th anniversary of the Great October Socialist Revolution 1917: Leningrad, 30-31 October 1967, Publication (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Item 12: The October Socialist Revolution and the International Trade Union Movement, 1967; Publication (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Item 13: Welfare Freedom Peace: Proceedings of the 34th session of the Executive Committee of the WFTU, 1967; Publication (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Item 14: Welfare Freedom Peace: Proceedings of the 34th session of the Executive Committee of the WFTU, 1967; Publication (Box 41, Folder 6)
- Box: 41, Folder: 7, Publication (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: International Day for Functional Literacy: Preparatory document for the World Trade Union Conference on Vocational training 1969, Publication (Box 41, Folder 7)
    Author: International Day for Functional Literacy
  - Item 2: International Day for Functional Literacy: Preparatory document for the World Trade Union Conference on Vocational training 1969, Publication (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Item 3: Land and Labour, 1968; Publication (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Item 4: Vocational Training: more than a concern - a necessity, World Trade Union Conference on Vocational Training, 1968; Publication (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Item 5: Vocational Training: more than a concern - a necessity, World Trade Union Conference on Vocational Training, 1968; Publication (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Item 6: Report on the second point on the agenda: Development of the WFTU's work in the United Nations and its specialised agencies, 1967; Publication (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Item 7: Report on the second point on the agenda: Development of the WFTU's work in the United States and its specialised agencies, 1967; Publication (Box 41, Folder 7)
- Box: 41, Folder: 8, Publication (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Federation Syndicale Mondiale: Reunion Consultative des Centrales Nationales Affiliees D'Europe - Expose du camarade Pierre Gensous Secretaire General de la FSM, 1971; Publication (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Item 2: The WFTU and the Struggle of the Arab Workers and Peoples, May 1976, Publication (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Item 3: The WFTU and the Struggle of the Arab Workers and Peoples, September 1975, Publication (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Item 4: The World Federation of Trade Unions and Vietnam: 1 - September 1967, Publication (Box 41, Folder 8)
    Notes: photocopy
  - Item 5: The World Federation of Trade Unions and Vietnam: 1 - September 1967 (cover page), Publication (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Item 6: The World Federation of Trade Unions and Vietnam: 1 - September 1967 (cover page), Publication (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Item 7: International Crisis of the Capitalist Monetary System -- Documents - Towards the 8th World Trade Union Congress, 1972; Publication (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Item 8: Human Progress Depends on Peace: Joint statement by the WFTU and WFSW on disarmament, 1975; Publication (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Item 9: Labor Manuscripts Description Worksheet, Publication (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Item 10: The Earth Must Not Become a Desert: Joint statement by the WFTU and WFSW on ecological problems, 1975; Publication (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Item 11: The Trade Unions and the United Nations, 1973; Publication (Box 41, Folder 8)